Today's lunch is rice made with eggplants grown in the garden.
First, prepare 4T oil, 2T minced garlic, and green onion,
Add 2T red pepper powder and stir-fry over low heat.
Next, prepare 2 eggplants and 1/2 onion,
Pour the seasoning. (Oyster sauce 2T, soy sauce 1T, sugar 1/2T, cooking wine 3T, water 4T)
Lastly, chop 2 cheongyang peppers and fry them carefully so as not to burn them.
Depending on your preference, you can add eggs and your favorite leafy greens to make it even more delicious.
When I grow vegetables in my garden, I cook a lot of vegetables.
And I learned the charm of vegetables that I didn't know about.
It is a dish made with simple ingredients, but it was delicious enough to serve to customers.
I heard somewhere that making pasta with miso is delicious.
And I'm really excited to do something I'm curious about!
Fry the prepared garlic, green onion and pepperoncino.
Next, add lightly undercooked pasta, 1 cup of noodles, 1t soy sauce, 1T unsweetened soybean paste, 1/4 cup chicken stock, 1t sugar, and 1 cup mushrooms and continue to stir-fry.
When the water boils, check the seasoning and season with salt or soybean paste.
If you prefer a low-salt diet, substitute vegetable broth for chicken stock.
This is a pasta that is especially curious about its taste.
and! It tastes very different from what I imagined!
It tastes healthy but addictive.
The taste of this pasta depends on what kind of miso you use, so I would recommend the low-salt miso.
It was an afternoon on a winter day, longing for spring.
However, there are foods we must eat before winter is over.
Ingredients: salmon, half a cup of water, kelp, 1T tsuyu, 1T soy sauce, 1T mirin.
First, marinate the salmon, the main ingredient, in the seasoning for 1 hour.
Cook the marinated salmon over medium heat.
Then add the remaining seasoning and bring to a boil.
Add the same amount of water, 1T soy sauce, and 1T soy sauce to the soaked rice and cook the rice.
Cook on medium heat for 10 minutes, close the lid and cook on low heat for 10 minutes, add salmon and wait for 10 minutes.
While waiting, prepare the marinade to be eaten with the salmon rice.
The ingredients for the sauce are chives, cheongyang pepper, 2T tsuyu, 1T mirin, 1T soy sauce, and sesame seeds.
This rice is my daughter's favorite dish, who loves salmon.
Sometimes, the temptation of instant ramen comes to me as well, but
I don't regret taking my time today to make this dish.
(I almost ate the rice cooker...)
Today's lunch is spicy tuna rice with vegetables.
Fry half a small onion and a tablespoon of minced garlic.
Then add 1T red pepper powder, 1/2T soy sauce, 1T sugar, 1T mirin, 2T red pepper paste,
Finally, a can of canned tuna without oil.
I like menus that have everything in one bowl.
Sometimes this kind of rice feels like a painting.
Of course, the tast was great too :)
Not long ago, I ate a unique and delicious gimbap at a tourist destination.
So I decided to try cooking it at home.
Thinly sliced ​​beef is dipped in flour and salted egg water and grilled.
Then add the thinly sliced ​​green onion, hot pepper, burdock root and carrot.
Since green onions are too spicy to eat, prepare them with a sweet-flavored dressing.
If this sauce is hard to find in your country, don't be discouraged.
If you only have dried seaweed for kimbap and rice with a little salt in your kitchen
For the rest of the ingredients, you can use whatever ingredients you like.
In Korea, more than 20 types of gimbap are generally made depending on the combination of ingredients.
However, I remember this gimbap because the ingredients were really unique.
In Korea, there is a typical menu eaten with kimbap.
It's tteokbokki.
The ingredients for the seasoning are 1 cup of kelp water, a little bit of radish, 5T red pepper paste, 2T soy sauce, 2T honey, 3T sugar, 1T minced garlic.
This is my favorite tteokbokki seasoning.
When the seasoning boils, add soft rice cakes and fish cakes.
Finally, add boiled egg, green onion and honey to finish cooking.
It is a recommended menu for a weekend lunch.
HAMI's restaurant opened :)
HAMI: "I want to eat spicy tteokbokki like Mom and Dad.."
Here's a delicious salad pasta recipe that my sister gave me.
The ingredients are salad greens, sausage, boiled eggs, and pasta.
Oriental sauce 6T, balsamic 2T, sweet chili sauce 3T, ketchup 0.5T, honey mustard 0.5T, minced garlic 0.5T
Since the sauce is for two people, mix only 1/3 with the pasta.
Put the prepared ingredients and sprinkle a spoonful of sauce to finish.
If you do not have oriental sauce, you can make it by mixing 4T soy sauce, 4T sugar, 3T vinegar, 3T olive oil, and 1T minced garlic.
I was a little skeptical about whether this was a healthy diet, but it is definitely a delicious way to eat vegetables.
It was a delicious lunch menu :)
There is a good menu for weekend mornings.
Fry green onion and garlic in olive oil and add tomatoes.
Then add 1 tablespoon of soy sauce.
I bake the bread while the tomatoes are ripe.
Finally, scramble the eggs and you're done.
Healthy and delicious weekend specials
I started my morning in a good mood with delicious food.
I found my favorite diet recipe book in a bookstore a few days ago.
I will introduce the most delicious menu among the recipes in the book.
Place the chopped crab meat and avocado on top of the rice.
And scramble the eggs and you're done.
If the rice is brown rice, it will be healthier.
1/2T soy sauce, pepper, a little crushed red pepper-
Some foods have very pretty colors and make me feel good.
The combination of these ingredients will be tastier than you might expect.
I cooked with these ingredients, how did they become so delicious? It was an amazing experience.
If you're on a diet, I can't... recommend this food.
Because it is so delicious that you will eat more and more! haha
The easiest combination of ingredients to make kimbap is
It will be carrots and eggs that are lightly sautéed with salt.
Beat the eggs well and fry them thinly.
Eggs are cut better when they are slightly cooled.
Season the rice with a little salt and sesame oil.
Make the seaweed with the rough side up, and spread the rice grains thinly as if they were pressed.
After the end of seaweed and rice grains meet and stick, press firmly.
I also try adding washed kimchi here.
Sauce: 1T soy sauce, 1T vinegar, 1T oligosaccharide, 0.5T mustard, 2T water
This kimbap can be dipped in sauce, but it is delicious to eat as it is.
Carrot, which was mainly a supporting role in Korean food, became the main character today :)
If you eat a lot of spicy food in your country, I want to let you know that there are also gimbap like this.
It is a kimbap made with fish cakes, cheongyang peppers and carrots.
Prepare between 2-10 peppers according to your taste. (I prepared 4, slightly spicy!)
Fry the chopped vegetables carefully so as not to burn them.
The seasoning ingredients are 1T oyster sauce, 1T soy sauce, 1/2T minced garlic, 1/2T oligosaccharide, 1/2T mirin. (Mirin is a cooking liquor made from rice)
When you stir-fry the seasoning and vegetables, the ingredients are ready.
Kimbap tastes best when it is freshly made and served.
So many Koreans like to make their own kimbap and eat it.
Since seaweed can be a little tough, it cuts better when cut with sesame oil.
Since this kimbap is spicy, it is served with mayonnaise.
Spicy but attractive kimbap-
Sometimes spicy foods help lower stress :)
On a rainy day, I think of hot soup or stew.
Oil 1T, sesame oil 1T, red pepper paste 1T, red pepper powder 2T
Fry the seasoning over low heat to make chili oil.
1/4 onion, 1T minced garlic, clam, 500ml water
Pumpkin, mushroom, red pepper, seafood powder 1T, salted shrimp 1t
Finally, add soft tofu, green onion, and egg yolk to complete
I thought this food was very Korean, but surprisingly, it is said that many foreigners are looking for it.
It was a delicious dinner.
It is a pork backbone that can be bought at a cheap price at the supermarket.
2 cups of makgeolli liquor, warm water, 4T soybean paste. Add 1 bag of mixed coffee and set aside.
If you wait about 30 minutes, the blood from the meat is removed and you can make clean food.
This is a dish I always make once in winter.
Add 3 liters of water, 4 spoons of soybean paste, 3 spoons of mirin, and green onions and boil for 30 minutes. (Mirim is a cooking liquor made from rice.)
While waiting, wash and prepare mushy leafy vegetables such as Ugeji(dried radish leaf )or aged kimchi.
Minced garlic 5T, red pepper powder 3T, anchovy fish sauce 2T, soybean paste 2T
If you prepare washed kimchi, reduce the amount of soybean paste so that the food is not too salty.
Finally, remove the green onion and foam from the pot,
Add seasoned vegetables and boil for another 15 minutes.
This was the food I ate after taking the most important test of my life.
That test was the college entrance exam.
So, every year in November, when the entrance exam is held, I think of this dish.
What food do you think of every year?
I think that food was probably the food you ate when something important happened in your life.
My daughter and I will be able to eat this food with me when they are a little older.
And the moment to toast together will come :)
Tonight's menu is a popular street market food.
Ingredients: 300g radish, 200g beef, 1 green onion, 2T sesame oil, 1T salt, 3T red pepper powder.
Fry the ingredients over low heat to avoid burning.
Add mushrooms, bean sprouts and poached taro stems.
As I put the ingredients, I should have prepared a pot with one bigger size.
The ingredients for the broth are 2 liters of anchovy stock, 3T of soy sauce, 1T of anchovy sauce, 1T of salt, 1T of minced garlic, and pepper.
If you don't have anchovy stock, add water and bring to a boil.
This is a recipe my mom told me she saw on YouTube.
My mom has 40 years of her culinary career, but she is still learning new recipes.
She would have made this dish for decades without a recipe.
But I like her willingness to learn new things all the time.
Hami says that when she sees red dishes, they all look like kimchi.
The reason this food is often seen in street markets is,
This is probably because it is a food that merchants who work until night while shivering in the cold have been looking for food.
I cooked HAMI's food white without adding red pepper powder.
She liked that radish had a sweet taste. cute :)
Kimchi stew is probably the most common dish in Korean households.
Add salt, pepper, mirin, ginger, and some minced garlic to the pork and wait for 10 minutes.
Ripe kimchi can be added as is, but it can be cooked prettier if prepared by rolling it over the meat.
Place the end of the kimchi toward the floor so that the kimchi does not come loose.
Add about 2 cups of kelp and anchovy broth.
Add 1 tablespoon each of soy sauce, red pepper powder, minced garlic, and mirin, and a little sugar.
Add 1/4 cup of kimchi broth and boil over medium heat for at least 30 minutes.
Finally, add the onion and hot pepper and cook for another 10 minutes.
Kimchi stew is always a welcome menu item.
And it's always a satisfying dinner menu :)
I remember this curry chicken stir-fry because it was the first dish I made when I was newlyweds.
Put the shredded potatoes in water to remove the starch, and shred the onion as well.
Add a spoonful of oil and a little salt and cook over low heat.
50g curry powder (Ottogi product), 1T minced garlic, 0.5T red pepper powder, 1 plain yogurt
Put the ripe potatoes on a plate first.
Mix chicken and seasoning and cook over low heat to complete.
There is a little red pepper powder and curry powder in this dish, but it is not spicy.
my daughter's plate
It is delicious if you add one more chilli to adult food.
My Little Daughter Who Loved Playing Princesses
Now that she is 5, she prefers pants.
HAMI found a bib we bought for her cousin.
Is this kind of food called fusion food?
My husband said he wanted a beer after a long time.
HAMI: It's too much beer!
HAMI: I want to toast too!
It was a pleasant evening spent with 5-year-old HAMI.
Tonight's dinner is fried vegitable rice bowl that I ate deliciously at a friend's house.
4T soy sauce, 4T water, 2T mirin, 2T sugar, 1 kelp
After boiling for 3 minutes, add katsuobushi and turn off the heat.
Prepare the sauce by sieving it.
Prepare the tempura ingredients with your favorite vegetables and cut them into appropriate thicknesses.
I prepared lotus root, shiitake mushroom, sweet pumpkin, sesame leaf, and shrimp today.
Mix 1 cup tempura powder, 1/2 cup carbonated water, and water.
Then beat the eggs and make a dough.
Fry the prepared vegetables one by one and you are done-
Warm tempura is always delicious :)
Sprinkle soy sauce over the rice and top with tempura to complete.
Your meal is ready :)
Crispy tempura and warm rice go well together.
it's christmas eve
In Korea, party food is mainly cooked for Christmas.
Put the vegetables fried in oil,
Wash the chicken thoroughly, sprinkle with salt, put it in the refrigerator, and cook it in the oven.
Roast chicken is going to be buttered on top, so it tastes better if you season it in advance.
(while preheating the oven)
4T room temperature butter, 1.5T minced garlic, minced parsley
Make a sauce of the right consistency and apply it to the chicken.
Spread evenly all over the chicken. :)
Fill the chicken with lemon, rosemary and whole garlic.
Bake in an oven at 200 degrees C for about 40 minutes.
Roast Chicken Finished
merry christmas -
Delicious waffle dough made without mixing
Ingredients: 2 cups soft flour, 1/4 cup sugar, 2t baking powder, 1t salt, 1 cup water, 1/3 cup cooking oil, 2 eggs.
This dough doesn't even need fermentation.
My daughter was still sleeping, so I only baked two waffles.
Top the waffles with fruit, unsweetened cream or jam and, most importantly, maple syrup.
Of course, hot coffee is not to be missed.
If you don't have a waffle machine, I recommend the banana pancakes.
Mix 1 ripe banana, 1 egg, 120ml milk and 1 spoon of oil.
90g flour, 1.5t baking powder, a little bit of baking soda and salt
I can now make 8 small pancakes.
A sweet scent begins to fill the house.
Sometimes pretty food tastes good too.
Served with a salad makes a great brunch menu.
I want to believe that maple syrup won't make us fat for some reason. ha ha ha
On a gloomy day, banana pancakes will make you feel better.
Another side dish that can be made with eggplant is eggplant pasta.
Add a pinch of salt to the pasta and while it boils, chop the vegetables.
Fry green onion, garlic and red pepper in oil like frying.
Add eggplant and salt
1 scoop of noodles, 1T soy sauce, 1T oyster sauce, 1T sugar (for 1 serving)
Add red pepper if you like it spicy.
Stir-fry noodles and seasoning to complete
I like eggplant because I eat delicious dishes that can be made with eggplant.
Here are my favorite sandwich recipes.
3 eggs, a little salt and sugar
Scramble the eggs to form lumps.
(Left) Mayonnaise 2T, Condensed Milk 2T (Right) Mayo 2T, Sriracha 2T
Place your favorite ingredients such as lettuce, cheese, and ham on the sandwich.
Put plenty of fluffy eggs.
The key to this sandwich is the sauce.
The combination of these sauces makes this sandwich very tasty. A satisfying meal! :)
I went out to the terrace to harvest the basil I was growing.
Cut slightly ripe tomatoes that retain the tomato flavor.
( Continuing to eat tomatoes... haha ​​)
This pretty tomato is called 'Heirloom Tomato', grown without genetic modification.
Boil the thin capellini pasta noodles, rinse and put on top.
Add olive oil, salt, pepper and basil to complete cold tomato pasta
It was a Chuseok holiday.
My family stayed at home, but thanks to HAMI, I felt the Chuseok vibe.
Today I'm going to make some side dishes.
My favorite lunch box menu, Kimchi stir-fried
Add perilla oil and 1 tablespoon of sugar and stir-fry, then add anchovy stock and boil to complete.
I recommend the anchovy broth because it has a different taste if you simply stir-fry it.
Fried chicken breast is also one of my favorite side dishes.
Prepare flour, eggs and breadcrumbs.
This is the easiest way to make chicken gas.
If the chicken breast is already cooked, lightly fry it and you are done.
Let the kimchi stir-fry cool for a while.
Put the rice in the lunch box.
My husband and I didn't eat a lot of lunch box because there was a cafeteria in the school.
But I have pleasant memories of the lunch box.
Old-fashioned lunch box stuffed with rice and side dishes
When my parents were young, it is said that eggs were very precious.
Now I want to present this lunch box to my mom.
How to eat this lunch box!
HAMI: Fail!
It is delicious even if you mix all the side dishes in the lunch box :)
It's been a long time since I made a side dish, and it was a fun time.
Another popular side dish is stir-fried walnuts and anchovies.
Anchovy is rich in calcium, so it is a good menu to make for children.
0.3T soy sauce, 1T sugar, 2T cooking wine, 1T starch syrup, a little bit of sesame oil
Fry over high heat.
For quail eggs that children like, add 3T soy sauce and 1T sugar.
Cover with a lid and wait until the water boils.
Contrary to my heart, I do not often make various side dishes for my children.
So, sometimes, when I have time, I make several side dishes.
Toss with 2 tablespoons of mayonnaise, then stir-fry in red pepper oil and seasoning.
Seasoning is red pepper paste 3T, starch syrup 3T, mirin 1T, sugar 0.5T
The point is to mix this menu quickly.
Side dishes to fill my refrigerator are complete :)
Lunch time always comes quickly.
Deciding on a lunch menu to eat alone is very simple.
Because you can choose your favorite food :)
I washed the small lettuce and sesame leaves from the garden last week.
Add a spoonful of oil, and chop the onion, pumpkin, mushrooms and pumpkin leaves.
2 hot peppers, 1T minced garlic, 3T soybean paste, 1T red pepper paste, a little bit of chopped dried anchovies
Fry over low heat,
Pour the kelp anchovy stock,
Finally, add mashed or squeezed tofu.
When the soup is drowsy, it is done.
What food will be on your table today?
I'm also very lazy sometimes so I can't cook.
But when I eat home-cooked food, my body feels the difference.
Some say 'what you eat tells you who you are'.
I appreciate you looking forward to what I cook.
Because that expectation sometimes makes me very diligent.
So I hope you have a healthy weekend with this delicious homemade recipe made thanks to you.